# **CHRISTOPHER KSIAZAK**

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

# **Summary**

Hello! I'm Chris, a developer born and raised in El Paso, TX. I enjoy learning new technologies and applying that knowledge in designing and creating web applications.

I am proficient in HTML, CSS and Javascript including various technologies such as React, Redux, and Nodejs. In my last position as a Software Engineer at E-Dealer Direct, I served as part of the core engineering team. Although I wasn't there for long, I produced designs and prototypes, discussed application architecture, and built the front end using React and Redux, and the api using Rails and Searchkick. Unfortunately, due to COVID-19 affecting the market, I was downsized as the company scaled back operations.

For the past year, I've attend Lambda School for Full Stack Web Development. I've worked with various, distributed teams of different skill sets (ranging from Data Science to UX design, as well as other developers) and planned through various projects.

# **Employment**

**E-Dealer Direct** 

El Paso, TX Mar. 2020 to Apr. 2020

**Software Engineer** 

- Created designs and prototypes for a new feature using Figma
- Built out React views that hook into Redux state and are updated via websockets (ActionCable)
- Learned Ruby on Rails and ElasticSearch to implement features

Unfortunately, due to COVID-19 affecting our market, I was downsized as the company scaled back.

#### C3i Solutions

El Paso, TX Mar. 2017 to Current

**Project Coordinator** 

- Worked in conjunction with our client, Castlight Health, across several time zones
- Transitioned our program through several of our client's product launches
- Maintained knowledge base with current issues
- Triaged bug reports to appropriate engineering teams
- Made data driven decisions through various reports from Salesforce and JIRA
- Analyzed flat files and API requests from Anthem

## **Projects**

#### SwagDragon

SwagDragon is a hassle free drag and drop store builder that allows you to sell items without keeping them in stock. We accomplish this by hooking in to a dropshipping service, so that when a user purchases one of your items, it gets created by our dropshipper and shipped directly to them.

This is currently a work in progress, but it is built using Nextjs, Styled Components, Redux, and Node.

#### SongSight

Songsight was built to help you find new songs based on songs you already love. For this application, I served as part of the front end team and worked alongside 3 other developers, a back end team, and a data science team. The frontend was built using React, React-Router, Redux, and Grommet for styling.

#### Ksiazak.dev

Ksiazak.dev is my personal portfolio page and where I typically go to test out new technologies. The current iteration is built using Nextjs, Styled Components, and MDX. I'm using a particle generator for the heading and Styled Components for the overall page styles.

#### Optimal Airbnb Pricing API

I was the sole backend developer and built this API using Nodejs/express. This product is meant for Airbnb users wanting to list their properties in Berlin and provides you with the optimal price for the area based on several factors. I worked with our data science, as well as our front end React team on API specifications and data design.

## **Contact**

- cksiazak@gmail.com
- ksiazak.dev
- **(915) 253-8705**
- **♥** El Paso. Texas
- **y** cksiazak\_dev
- in cksiazak
- C) cksiazak

## **Education**

Lambda School

Apr. 2019 to Current

## Skills

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML5

CSS (LESS/SASS)

**Javascript** 

React

Redux

Node

SQL Gatsby

Nextjs

PostgreSOL

Ruby on Rails

Elasticsearch

**React Native** 

Knexis

#### REPORTING, DOCUMENTATION, AND ANALYTICS

JIRA

Tableau

Confluence

Datadog Salesforce

ExactTarget